I knew you would come.
I'm sure you know how I feel.
I know some things have happened
between you guys and me
but you and I are
essentially very similar.
I wonder if that's the reason why Edward-kun doesn't want to see me.
Brother doesn't want to use the Philosopher's Stone.
That's funny.
You brothers were, you know...
We journeyed together to
get back that which we had lost.
That's everything that we are.
Are you in pain, Nina?
It's all right.
All preparations
are in order now...
Your body, as well as the lives which were provided by many animals...
All that's left now is to join them all together
with the Philosopher's Stone.
How did you know about me
having the Philosopher's Stone?
Simple reasoning.
Judging by the injuries to Archer, I could tell what had happened.
At the center of it was Scar,
the scarred man.
And then I heard that
you two had fled.
King Bradley only wants one thing: the Philosopher's Stone.
You knew?
About the Führer
being a homunculus?
Hey now, how many years do you think I spent in the 5th Laboratory, anyway?
They used to go there,
along with that other one.
That other one?
The one who raised and
is leading the homunculi.
Just a moment.
By any chance, is that person...
We'll talk later.
You have obtained something that
they wanted so bad they can't stand it.
Now, bring it out!
A real, genuine Philosopher's Stone!
Please do not touch me.
I am the Philosopher's Stone.
This is a surprise.
So that's the reason why
Edward-kun didn't come, is it?
Yes.
We don't know
what will happen to my body
if we use the Philosopher's Stone,
at least not until
we carefully research it.
He said he wanted to do something about the homunculi before then.
I know that Brother
is worried about me.
But I want to return Brother to the way he used to be.
If you know of
a way to do that...
Of course I do. I will teach you
how to use the Philosopher's Stone.
However, I want you to
let me use its power as well.
An equivalent exchange.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
Most of it has been disposed of.
These books are all worthless.
What kind of person was Dante-san?
She was a great alchemist,
one who inherited this crest.
Or that's what I thought.
What you thought?
She was positively ingenious in her knowledge of alchemy
and hid it completely.
Doesn't that go without saying?
I mean, we encrypt our secrets
about alchemy and record them too.
She was incorrigible about it.
If alchemy was for the good of mankind, why hide it?
She chose to live a life in the forest, where she wouldn't meet anyone.
For what reason?
I thought you would be thrilled.
Does this mean that you were just another ordinary person?
I'm leaving the forest
to live in the city—
among the people who need me.
So you're going to live your life
for the gratitude of others?
Then why don't you just go ahead and enlist as a State Alchemist?
Don't you...
Get out of here.
Don't you like other people?
How could I like them?
They're selfish creatures without any merit.
They learn how to use a little gunpowder, and there is nothing but war.
If they were to learn all of the secrets of alchemy,
how much calamity do you think would come about?
Even so, I am human!
And so are you!
There was one name that you could never utter in her presence:
Hohenheim of Light.
M-My old man?
Yeah.
Looks like she couldn't
bring herself to throw this away.
It's a love letter from
Hohenheim to Dante.
J-Just a minute!
I met Dante-san, and she was pretty old.
She looked like she was twenty years older than my old man.
That's not what the issue is.
This has the year written on it
in the Christian calendar.
The Christian calendar?
It was based on an ancient religion that isn't practiced now.
According to this, the letter...
was written four hundred years ago.
What does it mean?
I don't know.
Maybe the names are just the same.
It's possible that the one
controlling all the homunculi is...
You're jumping to conclusions.
But are you prepared for that,
just in case?
Sorry I couldn't be of any help.
It's okay. This is something we'll do by ourselves.
Sensei...
I'm sorry.
You fool...
It's about to happen?
If war breaks out in the north,
it'll be different from the civil uprisings
we've had up to now.
Sorry I'm laid up
at a time like this.
It's just about time.
Havoc, you won't get lonely.
You'll have another friend.
Sergeant Fuery,
some nasty athlete's foot
was discovered during your examination the other day.
It has already spread to your brain.
That's how it goes.
You won't be moving out either.
Not bad.
Surely, you jest.
Clearly, the north is
engaging in military actions,
and we cannot help but say that it would be foolish
to overlook this and take up the matter
of our already established borders again.
However, the Führer has
come to a wise conclusion.
We will gather our forces in the Briggs Mountains,
along the border to the north,
where we will purge
any and all infiltrators!
You who are assembled here today
are the best of the best
and will be the first ones there!
I'm sorry for all of these
difficult missions in a row.
I feel it's an honor.
I believe the suspicions
about you are unfounded.
This is my proof of that.
I will live up to your expectations,
Your Excellency.
I wish you good luck,
Brigadier General Roy Mustang.
Lt. Col.
Alex Louis Armstrong, support him well for me.
Yes, sir.
However, with our main forces
concentrated in the north,
I am concerned for
the defense of Central.
Do not worry.
Frank Archer is eager to help.
Archer?!
You mean, that man is still alive?
A job well done, Führer.
There are no legends of the
Philosopher's Stone in the north.
Even by fanning the flames of war,
there isn't anyone there who will be
driven to create a Philosopher's Stone.
That's all right. Your purpose this time
is the leadership of the military.
Anyone who comes near the
Philosopher's Stone is destroyed.
Those who are soldiers
are not excepted.
Then it's not just Mustang.
No.
Everyone who was involved with
the Hughes affair is going to die in battle.
Courtesy of Envy.
If you mean me, I'm right here.
Oh, I thought I told you
to wait up north.
I heard that he was here.
You're being rude, Envy.
Out of my way, you human poser!
I won't have you
talk to him like that.
He is a homunculus that appears to age
like a person and is one of my masterpieces.
Where is he?!
"He" who?
That guy!
The same way you made Pride and
Greed!
He's toying with me—toying with us!
Hohenheim of Light?
He's here, right?! Where is he?!
You miss your birth father?
Where is he?!
He's dead.
You're lying!
There's no way he could die!
I'm the one who will
kill him, after all!
I disrupted the union of
his spirit, body, and mind.
He's as good as dead.
It's not true! It's not true!
Why didn't you tell me?!
He was supposed to be mine!
Mine! Mine!
Mine!
His sons are still alive.
To hell with them!
Even once you hear that they have obtained a Philosopher's Stone?
They have a Philosopher's Stone?
That's right.
At this rate, those boys are going to take everything back.
I won't let them.
It's unfair, isn't it?
Those boys getting to take everything back,
while you, who should be
his dearest son...
are unable to obtain anything.
I want to see them...
the expressions on their faces when the
Philosopher's Stone is taken from them.
Their expressions when they lose everything.
"I'm going to Tucker-san's place."
Shou Tucker. I thought he ran away at Liore.
Hold on.
Why do you think Tucker called him there?
That's obvious.
To complete that useless Chimera of his.
It's his daughter.
Tucker learned a lot of things from the 5th Laboratory,
including things about
the Philosopher's Stone.
And since he knows,
the Fullmetal brothers will know
how to use the Philosopher's Stone too.
What are you thinking, Lust?
Wrath,
take care of everything
else here for me.
You're leaving?!
That's a good boy.
My word, your brother is a genius.
He struck upon this seven-sided transmutation circle right on the spot.
You mean, you just copied it?
I'd like you to say that
I expanded on it.
But still, the fact is, Edward-kun came very close to the truth.
He probably realized that this method could be used to activate the Philosopher's Stone as well.
Brother was concerned
about my body.
He just thought you should be giving precedence to regenerating your body.
He doesn't seem to have any interest in using the Philosopher's Stone.
Why not?
It's probably because...
Nothing...
Could you come
over here for me?
Tucker-san!
I'm going to have you
pay me in advance.
Don't worry.
Bringing Nina back to life
will be nothing at all for a
Philosopher's Stone as huge as this.
Please wait!
I'm still...
Nina, Nina, it will be soon now...
Tucker-san!
Al?
Al!
You dumbass!
You're looking well, for someone being pursued by the military.
I heard about what you are
from my brother.
I am who I am.
Wrong.
Don't try anything funny.
What are you hiding?
I told you I knew
what you were!
Wrath!
Today's the day
when I will have them!
Sorry, but they're not for sale!
S-Stop!
Wrath!
If you're going to beg for your life,
I'm not listening.
Oh, that's all right. If you want my arm or leg, take them.
I've got the greatest
Automail mechanic around.
She'll give me something even cooler.
What?
But answer me one thing—
if you take my arm and leg from me
and attach them to yourself,
will that make you human?
Even if I have to use Automail—
even if my whole body becomes armor,
so what?
I'm still human.
But what about you?
Shut up!
Lust! What are you doing?!
Get him!
If you don't kill him,
I'm telling you-know-who on you!
Get him, Lust!
You want to become human too,
don't you?
If there is a Philosopher's Stone, yes.
Your little brother went off to Tucker's place
and is learning how to do it.
If you find out how...
Lust, what are you saying?!
Would you...
make me human?
Lust!
What do you think you're doing?!
I told you.
Cut it out. Do you seriously think I would make you guys human?
Why not?
If you were to make us human,
you wouldn't be chased after any longer.
Your enemies would be gone.
You traitor!
What were we told?
You heard!
Once we delivered the
Philosopher's Stone, we would be made human!
I don't believe it...
You-know-who only wants the Philosopher's Stone to go on living.
That's why there have
been so many wars.
That person is not going to make us human.
That's okay.
I...
will become human
under my own power!
It's just as I was told.
"You can't trust Lust."
You're a nuisance, lady.
Let's go.
We have to hurry.
Sloth is going after your brother.
Do you know where Tucker is?
The factory where he worked
before he became
a State Alchemist is close.
Wait. Wait!
It's not as though
I promised you anything.
Why not?
I should be the one asking why!
Why do you want to become human?!
You guys are immortal and can
remain in your present forms forever.
I'm not sure why, but you
look like you enjoy your lives.
So why would you want to become human again?
That's such a cruel thing
for you to say.
In that case, why do you have to return your brother back to the way he was?
It's the same thing.
Hey!
This "you-know-who" person who's in charge of you—
by any chance,
is it someone I know?
Good question.
Once I become human,
I wouldn't mind telling you.
Don't forget,
I'm still carrying your weakness!
I won't forget.
There's no way I could forget.
Nina, is that right?
What happened?
That's great, really.
Alphonse-kun. Thanks.
It's Nina.
See? She knows what I'm saying.
Right, Nina?
Call me Papa, Nina.
Her soul...
Congratulations, Shou Tucker.
That was a magnificent human transmutation.
It's okay.
I'm not interested in
your soulless doll.
Only a powerful will is able to
keep a soul set in place.
Looks like that wasn't
possible for you.
Come along, Alphonse Elric.
We can't very well let such a precious Philosopher's Stone be diminished any further.
Diminished?
Brother, Brother, is this...
the Philosopher's Stone?!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 47: "Sealing the Homunculus"
Look, Sloth.
Your weakness is right here.